

Email: xinyu.shi@uwaterloo.ca

Website: https://xinyu-shi.github.io/

RESEARCH INTEREST

My current research focuses on **Human-Computer Interaction**, particularly, **Human-AI Co-Creation** and **AI-Powered Creativity Support Tool**. The goal of my research is to design, develop, and evaluate interactive AI systems that effectively incorporate human intent into the computation process in order to boost the productivity of creative activities. My research seeks to gain a deeper understanding of the flow of creativity and to enhance human intelligence and creativity.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science | advisor: Prof. Jian Zhao

University of Waterloo

Sept. 2021 – Present Waterloo, ON, Canada

B.Eng. in Software Engineering

Xiamen University

Sept. 2016 – Jun. 2020 Xiamen, China

PUBLICATIONS

C.1 De-Stijl: Facilitating Graphics Design with Interactive 2D Color Palette Recommendation

X. Shi, Z. Zhou, J. Zhang, A. Neshati, A. K. Tyagi, R. Rossi, S. Guo, F. Du, and J. Zhao. Conditionally accepted by ACM CHI 2023.

C.2 Real-World Blind Super-Resolution via Feature Matching with Implicit High-Resolution Priors

C. Chen*, X. Shi*, Y. Qin, X. Li, X. Han, T. Yang, and S. Guo. (* equal contribution)

In Proceedings of the 30th ACM International Conference on Multimedia (MM2022). Oral (Top 5%)

C.3 Teaching American Sign Language in Mixed Reality

Q. Shao, A. Sniffen, J. Blanchet, M. E. Hillis, X. Shi, T. K. Haris, J. Liu, J. Lamberton, M. Malzkuhn, L. C. Quandt, J. Mahoney, D. Kraemer, X. Zhou, and D. Balkcom.

In Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT, Ubicomp2021).

C.4 Accurate and Fast Classification of Foot Gestures for Virtual Locomotion

X. Shi*, J. Pan*, Z. Hu, J. Lin, S. Guo, M. Liao, Y. Pan, and L. Liu. (* equal contribution)

In Proceedings of the 2019 IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR2019).

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Waterloo

Waterloo, ON, Canada

Graduate Research Assistant in HCI | Advised by Prof. Jian Zhao

Design interactive Human-AI Co-Creation system to augment human creativity and productivity.

Sept. 2021 – Present

The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen

Research Assistant in CV | Advised by Prof. Xiaoguang Han

Research Assistant in CV | Advised by 1101. Alaoguang Tian

Shenzhen, China Dec. 2020 – Aug. 2021

Proposed an approach based on *Vector-Quantized GAN* for *Image Super-Resolution*.

Dartmouth College Hanover, NH, USA

Research Assistant in HCI \mid Advised by Prof. Xia Zhou and Prof. Xing-Dong Yang

Sept. 2019 – Apr. 2020

Leveraged wearable sensing technique and Mixed-Reality to facilitate American-Sign-Language teaching.

Xiamen University

Xiamen, China

Research Assistant in HCI | Advised by Prof. Shihui Guo Exploited *wearable devices*, i.e., smart insoles, for *VR locomotion* with learned *gesture recognition models*.

Sept. 2017 - Aug. 2021

HONORS AND AWARDS

Vector Scholarship in AI, Vector Institute | \$17,500 for one year

2021

International Doctoral Student Award, University of Waterloo | \$15,000 per year

2021

Award for Excellence in Academic Performance, Xiamen University | ¥5,000 per year

2017 - 2020

SKILLS

Programming: Python, C, C++, Java, SQL, Shell **Framework**: PyTorch, D3.js, Numpy, Sklearn